Milislav Demerec Papers 1919-1966 Mss.B.D394
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Hofmeyr, J. D., 1929-1931; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hollaender, Alexander, 1939-1958; 75 items (Box 11)
    Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Neurospora; Genetics -- Penicillium; Genetics -- Yeast
  - Holland-America Line, 1956; 6 items (Box 11)
  - Holloway, Bruce W., 1960-1964; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Honors., 1956-1961; 20 items (Box 11)
  - Hoover, K. B., 1962; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Hoover, Margaret E., 1935-1937; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Horticultural Society of New York, 1938; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Horvat, Victor, 1924-1930; 37 items (Box 11)
  - Hovanitz, William, 1947-1953; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Howland, Ruth B., 1936; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hoxie, R. Gordon, 1959; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hruby, Karel, 1948; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Huber, Wolfgang, 1956; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hudson, P. S., 1930; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Huettner, Alfred F., 1930-1938; 7 items (Box 11)
  - Hughes, Roscoe D., 1934-1936; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Hull, Fred H., 1930; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Humphrey, G. C., n.d.; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Humphrey, R. R., 1959; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Humphreys, Edward J., 1934-1935; 15 items (Box 11)
  - Huskins, C. Leonard, 1935-1947; 14 items (Box 11)
  - Hutchison, C. B., 1924-1939; 10 items (Box 11)
  - Hutt, F. B., 1947; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Ikeda, Yonosuke, 1956; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Ikeno, S., 1926-1927; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Inman, O. L., 1935; 2 items (Box 12)
  - International Biological Program, 1962; 4 items (Box 12)
  - International Genetics Symposium -Japan, 1956., 1955-1956; 22 items (Box 12)
  - International Information, 1940; 14 items (Box 12)
  - Invitations to receptions, dinners, etc., 1947-1960; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Folder 1, 1947-1956; 38 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1960; 23 items (Box 12)
  - Iowa State College, 1942; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Irish, D. D., 1937; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Ishidsu, Jun-ichi, 1964; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Ives, Philip, 1945; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Jacob, Francois, 1952-1962; 4 items (Box 12)
  - Jeener, R., 1954; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Jenkins, Merle T., 1925-1935; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Jesenko, 1921; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Johannsen, O. A., 1933; 1 item (Box 12)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1951; 3 items (Box 12)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1948-1949; 6 items (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Mychyle W., 1939; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Jones, D F, 1924-1933; 21 item (Box 12)
  - Jones, Frederick N., 1958; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Jorgenson, L. R., 1927-1929; 4 items (Box 12)
  - Joshi, Leela M., 1964; 7 items (Box 12)
  - Journal of the American Medical Association. Letter of Grace, Bryson, Szybalski and Demerec, 1952; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Journal of Bacteriology, 1955; 9 items (Box 12)
  - Journal of General Physiology, 1952; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Journal of Heredity, 1924-1943; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Jovic, Zlotojc, 1930; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Jucci, Carlo, 1939-1954; 21 items (Box 12)
  - Jury, 1962-1963; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Kajiabohn, Jacob, 1922; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Kalcar, Herman M., 1959; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Kanazir, Dusan, 1959; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Kappert, Hans, 1927; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Karminski, George, 1932; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Kaufmann, B. P., 1936-1962; 13 items (Box 12)
  - Keim, F. D., 1929; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Kellenberger, E., 1957; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Kelner, Albert, 1953; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Kerschner, Jean, 1949; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Kihara, Hitoshi, 1948-1958; 15 items (Box 12)
  - Kikkawa, H. (Hideo), 1934-1957; 26 items (Box 12)
    Bacterial genetics; Drosophila genetics; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Kimball, Dexter S., 1922; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Kimber Award Committee, 1956-1962; 16 items (Box 12)
  - Knight, Mrs. Frances G., 1956; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Koenig, John, 1938; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Koller, Peo Charles, 1937-1960; 3 folders (Box 12)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Radiation genetics; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1937-1945; 30 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1945-1954; 20 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 3, 1956-1960; 21 items (Box 12)
  - Kolmark, Gunnar, 1953; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Koltzoff, N K, 1934-1931; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Komai, Taku, 1928-1956; 2 folders (Box 12)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Fellowships, assistantships; Human evolution, physical anthropology; International Congress of Genetics; Mouse genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1928-1931; 8 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1932-1956; 21 item (Box 12)
  - Kondo, M. S., 1928-1962; 4 items (Box 12)
  - Koric, Mirko, 1922-1952; 2 folders (Box 13)
    Academic freedom; Political issues; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich
    - Folder 1, 1922-1933; 13 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1952; 33 items (Box 13)
  - Kossikov, K. V., 1957; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Kostoff, Dontcho, 1930-1945; 4 items (Box 13)
  - Kovacevic, Zeljko, 1929; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Krauss, F. G., 1928-1933; 5 items (Box 13)
  - Krieg, David R., 1958; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Krivshenko, J., 1951-1953; 8 items (Box 13)
  - Krizencky, J., 1930; 7 items (Box 13)
  - Krizevci, Yugoslavia. Royal Agricultural College, 1919-1922; 5 items (Box 13)
  - Krug, C. A., 1934-1935; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Kuleshov, N., 1930; 5 items (Box 13)
  - Kursanov, L. I., 1928-1929; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Kusukawa, Akira, 1957; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Kvakan, Paul, 1923-1940; 2 folders (Box 13)
    Publication; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1923-1930; 55 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1928-1940; 21 items (Box 13)
  - Kydd, David M., 1959-1960; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Landaeur, Walter, 1935-1945; 4 items (Box 13)
  - Larroque, P., 1949-1950; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Latarjet, R., 1955; 3 items (Box 13)
  - Latyszewski, Miron, 1952; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Laughlin, Clara, Travel Services, 1947-1951; 12 items (Box 13)
  - Lazarick, Joseph, 1940; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Lea, D. E., 1940-1946; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Lebedeff, Gabriel A., 1927-1943; 18 items (Box 13)
  - Lebedev, A., 1992; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Lectures, 1930-1966; 49 folders (Box 13-14)
    Bacterial genetics; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Evolution; Genetics; Genetics -- Mutation rates; Lectures, public speaking; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1935, 1935-1936; 35 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1936, 23 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1937, 25 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1938, 1 item (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1939, 3 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1940, 40 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1941, 7 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1961, 3 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1962, 10 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1963, 18 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1964, 20 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1965, 39 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures, papers, etc., 1966, 3 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures: Adelphi College, 1958, 11 item (Box 13)
    - Lectures: Adelphi College, 1959, 7 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures: Adelphi College, 1963, 3 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures: California Institute of Technology, 1961; 3 items (Box 13)
    - Lectures: Chemicals and Heredity, delivered at Carnegie Institution of Washington Trustees' Meeting, Dec. 1947, 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Development of bacterial resistance to chemicals...at N.R.C. conference on insect physiology. Cincinnati, Ohio, n.d.; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Discussion at meeting of New York Pathological Society; Nov.18,1950, 3 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: The fine structure of the gene. In: Molecular control of cellular activity (Lecture at Ann Arbor), 1960-1961; 8 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Frequency of deletions among spontaneous and induced mutations in Salmonella. PNAS, 1960; 2 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Gene. Reinhold, Encyclopedia of Biological Sciences, 1960; 13 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: The gene and its role in ontogeny. Sams data, 1956-1957; 4 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Genetic aspects of the radiation problem. State of New Jersey Department of Health, May 3, 1958, 3 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Genetic structure of the CYS-C region of the Salmonella genome, 1958; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Genetics and antibiotics (Pfizer Pasteur Centennial, Nov. 21, 1957), 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Genetics seminar (Australia, 1960), 1959; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Induction of mutations in individual genes of Escherichia coli by low X-radiation, 2 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Macy's conference, n.d.; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Mechanism of the origin of X-ray induced deficiencies in Drosophila melanogaster, 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Neutogenic potencies of some polycyclic hydrocarbons and of some Ago compounds (simplified version), 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: North Carolina State College, 1961, 14 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Oklahoma-Rockefeller 1955-1956, 5 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Origin of bacterial resistance to antibodies. J .Bact., 56: 63-74. 1948, 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Perspectives in genetics, n.d.; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Progress in genetics. Talk to Science Talent Search winners, March 4, 1949, 4 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Proline mutants of Salmonella typhimurium. Genetics, 1959; 2 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Review of Biochemical Aspects of Genetics (Biochemical Society Symposium. No. 4) Archives of Biochemistry, 1930; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Rockefeller, 1956-1957, 4 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Selfer mutants of Salmonella Typhimurium, 1963; 4 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Spontaneous and induced mutations, 1947; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Stanford University, 1964; 2 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Theory of the gene. Brookhaven lecture, n.d.; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: Threonine, Isoleucine and Isoleucine-Valine mutants of Salmonella Typhimurium, 1 item (Box 14)
    - Lectures: University of California. (see also Meridian R. Ball), 1960-1963; 30 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: University of Oregon, 1961; 3 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: University of Utah, 1964; 5 items (Box 14)
    - Lectures: University of Washington, 1961-1964; 9 items (Box 14)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1949-1957; 8 items (Box 15)
  - Lehman, Herbert, 1947; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Leonard, Warren H., 1953; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Leonian, Leon H., 1936; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Lerner, Michael, 1959; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Levene, Howard, 1960; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Lewin, Alfred P., 1964; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Lewis, Warren H., 1955; 2 items (Box 15)
  - L'Heritier, Ph., 1945; 4 items (Box 15)
  - Li, A. W., 1929; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Liebecq, Claude, 1950; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Lindegren, Mrs. Carl C., 1945-1949; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Lindstrom, E. W., 1923-1939; 17 items (Box 15)
  - Link, George K. K., 1929; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Little, C. C., 1932-1954; 13 items (Box 15)
  - Long Island University, 1960-1966; 25 items (Box 15)
    C. W. Post College; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Long Island Biological Association
  - Long Island University, 1965, 17 items (Box 15)
  - Longley, A. E., 1925; 9 items (Box 15)
  - Longley, W. H., 1932; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Lorkovic, Prof., 1938; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Love, H. H., 1949-1957; 4 items (Box 15)
  - Lowe, Dolores Oliphant, 1933; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Luce, W. M., 1937; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Ludwig, C. A., 1925; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Lüers, H., 1948-1955; 4 items (Box 15)
  - Luria, S. E., 1944-1955; 11 items (Box 15)
  - Lysenko controversy, 1949-1950; 11 items (Box 15)
  - Machado, Jose A. Jr., 1946; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Magill, W. I., 1950; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Mains, E. B., 1927; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Mainx, F., 1947-1957; 9 items (Box 15)
  - Mangelsdorf, A. J., 1925-1955; 10 items (Box 15)
  - Mangelsdorf, P.C., 1929-1963; 7 items (Box 15)
  - Mankowski, Z. T., n.d.; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Mann, Albert R., 1924; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Marchalonis, John J., 1961; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Marsh, Louise, 1929; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Marshak, Alfred, 1934; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Massey, Louis M., 1924-1958; 4 items (Box 15)
  - Matica Hrvatska, 1925-1926; 8 items (Box 15)
  - Matney, Thomas S., 1963; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Matsuura, Hajime, 1929-1933; 4 items (Box 15)
  - Mavor, J. W., 1930; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Mayorga, 1959; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1944-1952; 16 items (Box 15)
    Biographical and personal data -- Demerec, Rada; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Honors -- American Philosophical Society; Zoology -- Nomenclature.
  - Mazoti, Luis B., 1947; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McCarty, Maclyn, 1946; 4 items (Box 15)
  - McClintock, Barbara, 1932; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McClung, C. M., 1932; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McDougall, Kenneth, 1962; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McDowell, E. C., 1929; 2 items (Box 15)
  - McElioy, W.D.M, n.d.; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McKay, A. W., 1923-1924; 3 items (Box 15)
  - MacKnight, Harlan, 1940; 3 items (Box 15)
  - MacLean, F. T., 1931; 1 item (Box 15)
  - McLeod, Margaret, 1927; 3 items (Box 15)
  - Macmillan Company, 1945; 3 items (Box 15)
  - McMillan, R. A., 1929-1930; 5 items (Box 15)
  - McPhee, Hugh C., 1937; 1 item (Box 15)
  - Medical physics, 1947-1948; 11 item (Box 15)
  - Merriam, John C., 1930-1934; 6 items (Box 15)
  - Mersereau, J. Warren, 1951; 2 items (Box 15)
  - Metz, C. W. (Charles W.), 1920-1955; 4 folders (Box 15)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; International Congress of Genetics; Recommendations -- Brink, R. Alex
    - Folder 1, 1931-1934; 35 items (Box 15)
    - Folder 2, 1934-1935; 16 items (Box 15)
    - Folder 3, 1936-1955; 18 items (Box 15)
    - Folder 4, 1920-1930; 47 items (Box 15)
  - Middleton, Richard B., 1964-1965; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Miller, A. P., 1941-1947; 11 items (Box 16)
  - Miller, Albert, n.d.; 0 items (Box 16)
  - Miller, Dwight D., 1952-1959; 5 items (Box 16)
  - Milo, Otto, 1957; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Miran, K., 1931; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Mirsky, A. E., 1930; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1925-1954; 12 items (Box 16)
  - Miyake, T., 1959-1964; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Mladenas, 1928; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Modrone, N. Visconti di, 1951; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1928-1956; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Moewus, Franz, 1948; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Mohr, Otto L., 1933-1945; 9 items (Box 16)
  - Montalenti, G., 1939-1953; 8 items (Box 16)
  - Monty, Kenneth, 1963-1964; 7 items (Box 16)
  - Moran, R. G., 1924; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Morgan, Lilian V., n.d.; 0 items (Box 16)
  - Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1928-1949; 12 items (Box 16)
  - Moriwaki, Daigoro, 1947; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Moses, Mildred S., 1927-1937; 8 items (Box 16)
  - Mouromtseff, I. E., 1934; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Mudd, Stuart, 1952-1959; 8 items (Box 16)
  - Muller, Hermann Joseph, 1926-1948; 3 folders (Box 16)
    Bibliographical matters; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics; Publication; Research support; Russian politics and science; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1926-1930; 5 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1940; 32 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 3, 1940-1948; 33 items (Box 16)
  - Murphy, R. P., 1960; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Mutation Research, 1963; 6 items (Box 16)
  - Myers, C. H., 1931; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Nabours, R. K., 1938; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Nachtsheim, Hans, 1927-1949; 6 items (Box 16)
  - Nagai, Isaburo, 1929; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Naha, P. M., 1962; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Nassau County Board of Elections, 1956; 1 item (Box 16)
  - National Academy of Science. Office of International Relations, 1959; 7 items (Box 16)
  - National Academy of Science. Proceedings, 1952-1966; 4 folders (Box 16)
    Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Mouse genetics; National Academy of Sciences; Publication; Recommendations; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1952-1956; 39 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 2, 1957-1960; 15 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 3, 1959-1963; 33 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 4, 1963-1966; 23 items (Box 16)
  - National Academy of Science. Kimber Award, 1962, 3 items (Box 16)
  - National Audubon Society, 1945; 2 items (Box 16)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc. Science Committee, 1944-1946; 3 folders (Box 16)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1944-1945; 5 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 2, 1945; 3 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 3, 1946; 6 items (Box 16)
  - National Institute of General Medical Sciences, 1965; 8 items (Box 16)
  - National Institute of Health, 1965; 5 items (Box 16)
  - National Research Council. Chemical Biological Coordination Center, 1943-1963; 17 items (Box 17)
  - National Research Council. Committee on the biological applications of the electron microscope, 1947-1948; 8 items (Box 17)
  - National Research Council. General, 1943-1956, 9 items (Box 17)
  - National Research Council. Panel on genetic effects of radiation, 1943-1957; 2 folders (Box 17)
    Committee activities; National Academy of Sciences -- Committee on the Biological Effects of Atomic Radiation - Genetics Panel; National Research Council; Radiation genetics; Recommendations; Weaver, Warren
    - Folder 1, 1943-1956; 11 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1957; 17 items (Box 17)
  - National Research Council. Radiation committee grant, 1929-1932; 19 items (Box 17)
    Committee activities; Drosophila genetics; National Research Council; Publication; Radiation genetics; Research support
  - National Research Council. RCA Fellowship, 1940-1941; 23 items (Box 17)
    Committee activities; Fellowships, assistantships; National Research Council; Recommendations
  - National Science Foundation, 1953-1966; 4 folders (Box 17)
    Bacterial genetics; Drosophila genetics; National Science Foundation; Publication; Radiation genetics; Referee's report; Russian politics and science
    - Folder 1, 1953-1962; 8 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1957-1958; 8 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 3, 1960; 10 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 4, 1966; 4 items (Box 17)
  - National Science Foundation. Grant, 1965; 7 items (Box 17)
    National Science Foundation; Research support
  - Nature, 1959; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Nemec, B., 1933; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Nepal Curio House, 1957; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Neubauer, R., 1945; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Nevalonnyj, M., 1936; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Navashin, M., 1930; 5 items (Box 17)
  - Neal, Paul A., 1945; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Nebel, B. R., 1936-1941; 9 items (Box 17)
  - Neel, James, 1940-1942; 12 items (Box 17)
  - Neely, J. Winston, 1957; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Neethling, J. H., 1931; 2 items (Box 17)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1935; 4 items (Box 17)
  - Nicholas, John S., 1960; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Nijhoff, N V Martinus, 1932; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Nilsson-Leusoner, G., n.d.; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Noache, Konrad L., 1927; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Nomenclature correspondence, 1963-1965; 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Folder 1, 1963; 9 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1963; 14 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 3, 1963; 13 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 4, 1964; 12 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 5, 1965; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Nomenclature history, 1939-1956; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Folder 1, 1952-1956; 7 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1952-1956; 4 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 3, 1939; 4 items (Box 18)
  - Nomenclature, terminology, symbols, bacterial genetics, 1963; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Folder 1, 1963; 30 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1963; 13 items (Box 18)
  - Novick, Aaron, 1955; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Novokovic, 1929; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Oliver and Boyd, Ltd., 1968; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Oliver, C. P., 1933-1938; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Oparo, L., 1956; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Osborn, John J., 1954; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Other appointments, 1942-1957; 50 items (Box 18)
    Editorial matters; Honors; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Page, Arthur W., 1947; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Page, Walter H., 1959-1960; 18 items (Box 18)
  - Paillard, Ltd., 1959; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Painter, Theophilus, 1934; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Pal, B. P., 1957; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Papin, M., 1922; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Park Davis and Co., 1956; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Park, Sang Won, 1964; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Parnell, F. R., 1927; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Patterson, J. T., 1933-1945; 17 items (Box 18)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1958; 4 items (Box 18)
  - Pavan, C., 1947-1964; 4 items (Box 18)
  - Peabody, M., 1956; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Pearson, Helen, 1955; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Pearson, Jay F. W., 1932-1938; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Pecija, W., 1924; 4 items (Box 18)
  - Pellew, Caroline, 1930; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Penicillin project, 1942-1947; 5 folders (Box 18)
    Bacterial genetics; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1947; 15 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1947; 31 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 3, 1945-1946; 39 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 4, 1944; 41 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 5, 1942-1944; 48 items (Box 18)
  - Perrenboom, C. A., n.d.; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Peters, Myrna M, 1963; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Petry, Loren C., 1926; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Pevalek, Ivo, 1924-1926; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, 1922; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Phipps, J. F., 1925-1929; 9 items (Box 18)
  - Pifer, Alan, 1958; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Pincus, J. W., 1935-1936; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Pipkin, Sarah Bedichek, 1939-1940; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Plough, H. H., 1934-1954; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Plunkett, C. R., 1929-1932; 14 items (Box 18)
  - Poison Ivy pills, 1945; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Pontecorvo, G., 1944-1959; 18 items (Box 18)
  - Popovic Pecija, Emil, 1930-1932; 35 items (Box 18)
  - Poser, Max, 1936; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Poulson, Donald F., 1937-1950; 14 items (Box 18)
  - Prawochenski, R., 1925-1936; 5 items (Box 19)
  - Premo Pharmaceutical Laboratories, Inc., 1956; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Pritchard, R. H., 1963; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Proluaskin, L, 1929; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Punnett, R. E., 1926-1930; 5 items (Box 19)
  - Radiation Research Society, 1932-1954; 14 items (Box 19)
  - Radoscogeric, P. R., 1922-1924; 5 items (Box 19)
  - Rajewsky, B., 1955; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Raleigh, H. J., 1931; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Rand, Frederick V., 1925-1926; 10 items (Box 19)
  - Randolph, L. F., 1925-1959; 13 items (Box 19)
  - Ravenikar, S., n.d.; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Ravin, Arnold W., 1963; 6 items (Box 19)
  - Recommendations, 1939-1966; 22 folders
    Recommendations
    - Recommendations, 1939-1942., 1931-1942; 26 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1943-1945, 13 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1946, 19 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1947, 4 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1948, 18 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1949, 9 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1950, 6 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1951, 23 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1952, 28 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1953, 4 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1954, 22 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1955, 8 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1956, 24 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1957, 40 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1958, 27 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1959, 5 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1961, 9 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1962, 10 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1963, 22 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1964, 23 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1965, 49 items (Box 19)
    - Recommendations, 1966, 13 items (Box 19)